Clayton Strickland

Atlanta, GA

256.318.4202 cjstrickland5@gmail.com github.com/RdDvls

SUMMARY

I'm an ambitious learner with a wicked attention to detail and great adaptability. I learn best through researching and hands-on experience, and I've perfected this approach in my passion for creating good food. Now that I've learned Java, I'm ready to take on new challenges in tech!

SKILLS

Java

JavaFX

Threads

Sockets

JDBC

Hibernate

Spring

JUnit

Test Driven Development

Agile Development

JavaScript

AngularJS

CSS

IntelliJ w/ Debugger

Git & Github

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

The Iron Yard | Atlanta, GA A Back-end Engineering with Java Student

The Iron Yard is a 12-week coding bootcamp specializing in highly focused, immersive training centered on language fluency, object-oriented programming, and project-based learning.

- Music Theory Trainer
 - Final project focused on developing the user's ability to identify scales and intervals in music; Designed to be an instructional aid rather than a game
- Make Chocolate
 - Our first front-to-back project, the logic of which was built in Java and the UI was built with AngularJS;
 First work with UI design
- TIY Banking System
 - Project assigned in week 2 of 12 that introduced multiple background threads, user and data tracking, as well as writing to file

Fatback Pig Project | Eva, AL Artisanal Butcher

2015 - 2016

2011 - 2012

Aug 2016 - Oct 2016

Fatback Pig Project provides immersive butcher training under experienced professionals. This experience taught made me to value learning by trying and failing before executing.

 Performed highly precise butchering techniques on expensive products as part of training

Goin' Coastal Seafood | Atlanta, GA Garçon de Cuisine

- Maintained a laser-focused attention to detail in each dish, its preparation, and presentation while working with and managing a team in a fast-paced, demanding, and ever-changing environment
- Constantly researched and learned new skills and techniques in order to excellently prepare each new menu
- Handled Kitchen Manager duties as needed

EDUCATION

University of Alabama

2012 - 2015

Pursued a degree in Civil Engineering with an Environmental Engineering focus